Paulo Leonardo Benatto

Florianopolis, Brazil benatto@gmail.com +55 (48) 99767365

Summary

Bachelor in computer science having expertise in software development, good professional relationship and focused at work. With 6 years of professional experience in software development using basically, C/C++, I am now looking for new challenges and opportunities that allow me to learn new technologies and work with new people.

Education

Universidade Estadual do Oeste do Parana (UNIOESTE), BS in Computer Science, December 2007.

Experience

SEC+

Dec 2012 - Present

System Analyst

Main Tecnologies: Linux, Python, Django Framework, JavaScript and C;

- C ANSI development to analyze ELF binaries. MalELFicus project;
- Development of tests with *CUnit*;
- Software documentation with doxygen and/or gtk-doc;
- Backend development with python/django (Intermediate);
- Frontend development with JavaScript. GoogleMaps API v3. (Intermediate);
- Database *PostgreSQL*;
- Agile development with SCRUM;
- *GNU/Linux* administration;

Digitro Technology - NDS

Jan 2012 - Dec 2012

System analyst

Main Tecnologies: Linux, C ANSI, shellscript, protocols: HTTP, SIP, UDP, TCP;

- Software development of collection and interception of data used in police and judicial investigations.
- Development of parsers for data gathered from Facebook, WhatsApp, general email, IRC and others.
- Test Driven Development (TDD) with CUnit;
- Automatic build with JHBuild;
- Continuous integrations with Jenkins;
- Software documentation doxygen and/or gtk-doc;
- Libraries: GLib, PCAP, Iconv, and others;
- Agile development with SCRUM;
- GNU/Linux administration;

Digitro Technology - STE

Set 2008 - Dec 2011

System analyst

Main Tecnologies: Linux, VoIP, C/C++, shellscript, protocols: UDP, TCP, SIP;

- FreeSWITCH administration;
- OpenSER administration;
- Development of SIP protocol on a softphone;
- Development of interface using the EFL (Enlightenment Foundation Libraries) stack on a IPphone;
- GNU/Linux adminsitration (Debian and CentOS);

- Development Tools: VI, GCC, make, cmake, VisualStudio, Splint, Valgrind, gdb and subversion;
- Document database: mongodb;
- Automate tasks with shell script and python;

Virtual Office

Jan 2008 - Aug 2008

Developer Jr

Main Tecnologies: Linux, VoIP, SIP, Asterisk and Latex;

- PBX IP Asterisk administration;
- Debian GNU/Linux adminstration (shell script);
- Web development solutions using PHP, HTML, CSS and MySQL;
- Development of a document, in latex, about Asterisk software;
- Customer Support VoIP;

Skills Base

Operating System: Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS and others), Windows NT/XP/Vista/7 and OSX;

Network Protocols: IP, TCP, UDP, HTTP, SIP, FTP, SMTP, SNMP, e outros;

Progamming Languages: C/C++, Python, JavaScript, plus some experience with lua / Java / Ruby / PHP / HTML;

Virtualization: VirtualBox, VMWare, plus some experience with Xen;

Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Intermediate in English and Spanish;

Projects

In my spare time I develop some open source projects (https://github.com/patito/).

- libpenetra: The libpenetra was created with the goal of studying the windows binary format known as Portable Executable (PE). With libpenetra you can access all information about PE binaries. (https://github.com/patito/libpenetra)
- libmalelf: The libmalelf is an evil library that SHOULD be used for good! It was developed with the intent to assist in the process of infecting binaries and provide a safe way to analyze malwares. (https://github.com/SecPlus/libmalelf)
- malelf: Malelf is a tool that uses libmalelf to dissect and infect ELF binary. (https://github.com/SecPlus/malelf)

More Info

- Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/benatto
- Github: https://github.com/patito